[♪ "Away From the Castle" plays]
[Grey] Before we operate,
we place drapes over our patient,
exposing only the area
where we'll be working.
They not only help us focus
on what we need to see,
but they keep the field clean
and minimize debris getting in the way.
Incoming... [sighs]
...and I don't have a lot of time.
Do you wanna use one of
our other three bathrooms to vomit?
[shushes] I feel decent for the first time
in weeks, so don't jinx it.
And don't forget we have
our first OB appointment today.
- I thought that was after work.
- It is.
So what's the rush?
Well, the kids are still asleep,
my charts are done,
and I've got just enough time
for a quick shower.
How quick?
If it's too quick, I'll kill you.
[Grey] Drapes are specialized
to fit the needs of various surgeries.
The challenge comes when there's
a complication under the drape.
Oh, and we switched to a new EMR now.
You select the medication on top
and then scroll all the way down
to enter the dosage.
- Makes no sense.
- Medication up top.
Dosage on the bottom. Got it.
And you're only allowed
two pairs of scrubs now.
- It's all automated...
- Miranda, I've been a resident before.
- I'll be okay.
- You're not nervous?
I feel great. It's like coming home.
Dr. Bailey, welcome back.
Yeah, welcome back to the both of you.
Oh, Warren, do you... do you know Dr. Ndugu?
What, are you kidding?
Tore up the dance floor at his wedding.
My moves were basically a meme.
I was like... [grunts]
- [Miranda] How's Catherine?
- Feeling better every day.
Especially now that we know
the biopsy results were negative.
Thank God.
She wants to throw a party.
Caviar and champagne, and not the kind
you get from your regular grocery store.
[chuckles] I'd expect no less.
Send her our best.
- Will do.
- Okay. [chuckles]
This means stop talking.
What?
[sighs] Ndugu and Pierce
are getting a divorce.
- Oh.
- Yeah.
[Grey] When the body's draped,
we can't see something going pale
or a leg turning blue.
I refuse to be late
on Bailey's first day back.
Tell that to the guy
who took a 20-minute shower.
- Says the guy who doesn't live there.
- Hey.
[panting] There was a fistfight
on my bus. I thought I was gonna be late.
Hey. Where's your sister?
- We wanna meet your mini-Mika.
- [Mika] Late.
And we're not alike at all.
[horn honks]
[Grey] When we can't see the whole body,
we might miss
a telltale sign something's gone wrong.
Thank you.
Sorry. [sighs]
I left my phone on the plane, and the line
for the bathroom was really long,
and then Dumbledore
missed the freeway exit.
My ride-share driver looked just like him.
I couldn't unsee it. [chuckles]
Not alike at all.
That's Lucas, aka Skywalker.
Simone, Blue... [sighs] ...and, uh, Jules.
Hi.
This is my youngest sister,
Chloe. [chuckles]
I have cancer.
Don't be late for Bailey.
We'll see you later.
Come here.
It's gonna be okay.
Dr. Webber's the best.
We'll figure this out.
Come on.
Huh?
Here's the overnight roster list.
You need to follow up on Ms. Borgman's CT,
and there are two rule out appy consults
in the ER waiting for ultrasounds. [sighs]
Good morning to you too.
Not all of us
just spent two weeks in Paris.
Clearly. Mmm.
This is nothing like a café crème.
Will you just take this so I can go home
and face-plant into my pillow?
- Morning.
- Good morning.
I mean, hi. I... Hey.
This is James, the hospital chaplain.
Enchanté.
Taryn.
You work nights?
I work when I'm needed.
Is that from the coffee cart?
[clicks tongue] Uh, no.
I drink French now.
It's Le Gateau Jolie down the street.
Ah, okay.
[inhales] I could use some coffee.
Would you wanna go for a walk?
Oui.
Ooh, that's French for "yes." [chuckles]
[Levi clears throat]
Nice to meet you.
- [doctor] Welcome back, boy. [chuckles]
- [chuckles]
So, Bailey's her husband's boss?
Is that allowed?
One of your aunts is
head of the neuro department,
and your other aunt's name
is on the building.
Heron hired him before she left.
Everyone says he's impressive.
- Bring it. You all slow me down.
- Oh, my God. He's not your competition.
He is a fourth-year on a trial basis
until the ACGME approves him to stay.
Oh, there's a finite number of people
who can fit around an operating table.
Everyone is my competition,
including Mr. Doctor Bailey.
Uh, it's Warren, actually.
Ben Warren.
Looking forward to working with you again,
Dr. Kwan.
I see you've met Dr. Warren.
Yes, he is my husband.
No, he will not be getting
special treatment.
As for the rest of you, any bad habits
you picked up while I was gone,
lose them.
You have four months left
in your intern year.
I want you sprinting to that finish line,
understood?
All right. Helm has your assignments.
Any problem,
she'll be happy to hear about it.
- Get to work.
- Okay.
Griffith is with Ndugu.
Warren and Kwan, to the pit.
Adams and Millin, with me.
- Uh...
- Oh.
[announcer 1] Dr. Okana to Peds ICU.
Dr. Rachel...
[groans] A hundred unread emails
after operating all night.
Why do I like this job again?
- Were you in the OR?
- [scoffs] Yeah.
Nasty bus accident at the airport.
I was called in around 4:00.
- Kids are at my mom's.
- Oh, no.
Why didn't you call me?
I didn't wanna disturb you
while you were in surgery. What's wrong?
I had muffins and bagels delivered
to the house
because you've been
on the morning routine so often,
and I wanted to take care of breakfast
for you.
- You should've said something.
- It was supposed to be a surprise.
Do you think your mom
could go over there and grab them?
I am in back-to-back meetings,
and Richard wants the quarterly budget
report before it goes to the board.
- Sounds like you need a break.
- That is the opposite of what I need.
Trust me. I had your job.
You have to pace yourself.
This job is very different
than the job you had ten years ago,
but, um, thanks for the tip.
I'm just trying to help.
I have to go fire
an anesthesiologist. [sighs]
[Lucas] Hey,
you said we'd be saving lives.
I said you'd be helping to save lives.
You are contributing to
one of the most memorable experiences
in a medical student's education.
Providing the opportunity
to learn human anatomy
while developing their own understanding
of what it means to be human.
- Are those...
- I hate this already.
Cadavers for Ander-Simmons's
med school anatomy lab.
We scan them so students have images
to help them diagnose
how their cadavers died
during their anatomy class dissection.
Good luck.
[stammers] You're not helping?
[speaking French]
Pretty sure that means we're screwed.
[both groan]
- [announcer 2] Dr. Koreskos to Peds.
- [breathing heavily]
Dr. Vivian Koreskos to Peds.
Dr. Ndugu.
Am I getting out of here today?
This pneumonia's taking up
all my field time.
I'm supposed to be out
blocking a half-time show.
[clicks tongue] Mr. Riley's
a high school band director.
You win the state championship
three times in a row?
Uh, come on. Don't take the fourth one
away from me. [chuckles]
Well, we'll make this quick
so you can get back to it, all right?
Dr. Griffith.
Darren Riley, 55,
history of smoking and pulmonary fibrosis.
Admitted for multi-drug-resistant
gram-negative pneumonia.
Currently on 7 liters nasal cannula
and Vanc-Zosyn.
Ah, there's music in the voice.
- You sing?
- No, but I marched in high school.
Birds of a feather.
- Which instrument? [coughs]
- Trombone.
[chuckles] Former bone player
and a doctor.
That's not bad.
- It's not.
- [Darren chuckles]
- Sats are low despite the nasal cannula.
- Okay.
Uh, let's put him on high flow
and then get him to CT.
Dr. Griffith's gonna take you
for some scans.
More scans?
We're doing everything we can
to get out of here, okay?
Stay close. No local family,
and his last ABG came back borderline.
I reviewed your scans with radiology.
There is some
suspicious-appearing lymph nodes.
It's likely stage 3B rectal cancer
due to the...
Wait, 3B?
I thought it was 2A.
Mimi, can you just stop moving?
Sorry. [sighs]
[Richard clears throat]
Okay. Uh, what happens next? [sighs]
Chemotherapy, radiation?
Correct.
Surgery's a possibility,
depending on the tumor's response.
Will I lose my hair?
It's possible.
What other side effects are there?
It varies from patient to patient.
Radiation often causes
impaired ovarian function.
There is nausea and fatigue,
and changes in mood
and weight are common too.
I won't be able to have kids?
We'll have you talk to an ob-gyn
about your options.
Do you have any other questions
for me? [distorted]
[Chloe] How long does chemo usually take?
[Richard, distorted]
Wait. So, you went from Wyoming
to Raleigh to St. Louis to Seattle?
There were a bunch of places in between.
Uh, I did the whole global nomad thing
before divinity school.
I've only ever lived here.
But you travel, right?
Well, I used to visit my grandparents
in Illinois.
Wait, but then how did you end up
becoming a chaplain?
I grew up in Wyoming
with two devout episcopal parents.
[stutters] I love them,
but it was, uh, complicated.
Was it like a...
like a hard coming out thing or...
No, not really. Um...
Uh, I'm an only child,
and I always felt this pressure
to be their everything.
And, uh...
I don't know, I-I needed space.
So, left home, never looked back,
and then they died.
I'm so sorry.
[stammers] I wish I had a more
noble reason for becoming a chaplain,
but truth is, I only really found
my faith again because of grief and guilt.
Sometimes you have to help yourself
in order to help others.
That's very poetic.
That's my mother. [chuckles]
She's a whole other conversation.
[chuckles]
I have time.
Wanna get lunch?
Yeah.
[ER doctor] All right. Roll him up to CT.
Daniel will be there in two minutes.
[ER doctor 2]
They told us to come in at trauma 1.
Warren, nice to see you back this side
of the ambulance bay.
- You back full time?
- On a trial basis for now.
But don't go easy.
I'm just another resident.
Well, why don't you warm up
with some sutures?
We have a small thigh lac in bed three.
I just gave her some lido.
And, Kwan, you can help him out.
After you.
Uh... Ms. Dunn.
I'm Dr. Warren, and this is Dr. Kwan.
Judith is fine.
Not Judy.
Judy is my mother,
and she talks to her plants.
- Judith it is.
- [Judith chuckles]
It says here you have a cut on your thigh.
All right, let's take a look.
- Roll over, please.
- [grunts] Okay.
[Judith grunts]
[Judith sighs]
[Ben sighs]
It was my own dumb fault.
Six-inch stilettos and tequila don't mix.
Oh, what was the occasion?
The tequila was for my friend's birthday.
Heels were for my new peach.
[chuckles] I got a BBL two months ago.
A Brazilian butt lift.
Oh. [chuckles] We're familiar.
Careful, Doctor. All that drool
could stain your white coat. [chuckles]
No. No, no. It's, uh...
It's not what you think.
Um...
I grabbed the wrong sutures.
Can you grab me a 4-0 Monocryl?
Thank you.
I-I was just getting a better suture
for your cut.
How are you feeling?
You need more lidocaine?
I don't feel the cut anymore, but...
[grunts] ...it's my hip that's killing me.
From the fall?
I finally feel well enough to take
this booty out for a spin,
and now my hip's hurting like hell.
It's probably just bruising, but we'll
get some labs and X-rays just to be safe.
Uh, can you grab the labs
and I'll take care of the X-rays?
You got it, boss.
[sighs, grunts]
[both grunt]
Oh, why is it that everybody
who donates their body to science
- weighs 800 pounds?
- They don't.
They just can't change
their center of gravity like live people.
- They're literally dead weight.
- Okay.
- Can you hold your side up more?
- I am.
- He's sagging.
- I don't think he cares.
[both grunt]
[huffs]
Well, the good news is, uh,
we only have 29 left of these. [panting]
What's the bad news?
- [sighs] He's on feet first.
- [groans] No.
[sighs]
[clicks tongue]
[clears throat] Uh, Griffith,
how busy are you?
I'm almost done inputting orders
for Dr. Ndugu,
and then I should start rounds
in about 20 minutes.
- Oh, just enough time to run to the pit.
- You need something there?
There are a couple of patients
on Dr. Hunt's service.
Can you check on them for me?
You need me to add someone
to my roster list?
Oh, no, no.
Uh, just see how things are going.
Like, check and see if the patients
are satisfied with their care here?
[stammers] Um, you don't need
to say anything to them.
Just discreetly observe.
See how the patients are doing.
See how the doctors are doing.
Got it. And then I should circle back
with you after?
Took the words right out of my mouth.
[chuckles]
We typically recommend
hormone replacement therapy
for the loss of estrogen production
and fertility.
So that would allow me
to have kids later if I want?
Well, there's no guarantees.
But if you wanna increase your chances,
many patients opt to retrieve
and freeze their eggs.
What do you think?
Uh, it'll take at least a month
to do a round of egg retrieval.
That's if your body responds to
the hormones correctly.
The cancer could spread to a later stage
during that time.
There are other options, right?
At this time, egg freezing
is the most effective and common.
Okay. Well, find something else.
Look at other colorectal cancer cases,
meet with your department.
- Yasuda...
- There has to be a way.
It's okay, Mimi.
I'm not sure I really want kids anyway.
Warren.
Nice to see you back.
What do we got?
Thirty-four-year-old female,
history of type 2 diabetes,
tripped and fell onto her
left thigh three days ago.
Sustained a thigh laceration
but has pain with weight bearing
that's getting more severe.
- How are her labs?
- Still waiting.
- I just called to put a rush on it.
- Hmm.
You think it's a hip joint effusion?
[Atticus] I couldn't tell you.
This is a lateral hip. I need an AP view.
[stutters] I don't know what happened.
I ordered an X-ray series.
The system is a little funky.
You gotta go to the drop-down
to order the AP view.
Hip joint effusions
are difficult to see on X-rays.
- A CT scan would give better visibility.
- [stammers]
Kwan's right.
- Page us when you've got it.
- [clears throat] Mmm.
- You want me to show you how to...
- No. [stutters] I got it. I got it.
[sniffs, sighs]
- Oh. Ah.
- Whoa.
Oh.
[sighs]
Are you okay?
Chloe's cancer is more advanced
than we thought.
I'm so sorry.
Webber asked Dr. Sugihara
to see her. [sighs]
- Chief of oncology. That's good.
- It's terrible.
She has to start chemo
and radiation right away,
which means she doesn't have time
to protect her fertility.
Oh. I mean, does she want kids?
She's 22.
She doesn't know
what she wants for breakfast tomorrow.
She's the eighth out of eight sisters.
She spent her whole life getting dragged
to our practices, our recitals.
She only ever had hand-me-downs.
Always had to watch us on the roller
coasters because she wasn't tall enough.
And now that she's finally out of our
shadows and starting to live her own life,
this.
Her future should be wide open,
not limited by an awful disease.
Well, at least she'll still be alive.
- What is that supposed to mean?
- Nothing.
I'm just trying to look
on the bright side.
My sister has cancer.
There is no bright side.
But you wouldn't get that, would you?
Because you don't have sisters.
You have one brother
who thinks celery juice changes lives,
and you don't even like him.
So please don't pretend to understand
what this feels like.
You never will.
[sighs]
No. No way.
You're living in complete fantasy.
- You asked my opinion.
- Well, I wasn't expecting it to be wrong.
I am a man of science.
I don't know what else to tell you.
The Millennium Falcon
can go faster than light.
It has hyperdrive.
That thing breaks down more often
than my mom's old Ford Taurus.
It made the Kessel Run
in under 12 parsecs.
The Kessel Run tests navigation,
not speed.
The Enterprise is exponentially faster.
- How do you figure?
- Warp 1 is the speed of light.
Even the original Enterprise
went up to warp 5. Who are you?
So you would rather be the captain
of the Enterprise than Han Solo?
- Obviously.
- Do you wanna go back to my place?
Obviously.
[chuckle]
[grunts]
[panting]
[both chuckling]
- Hey, hey, hey, hey.
- [chuckles]
- I thought you were on cardio today.
- [chuckles] What? I am.
I had to run downstairs for something.
- Well, I'm, uh, glad I got to see you.
- [sighs]
Mmm.
[door opens]
Hi.
- [chuckles]
- [door opens, closes]
[smacks lips] Can I ask you
a hypothetical question?
Yeah.
If you were asked to review
a colleague's performance,
and they made an inconsequential mistake,
would you mention it?
[smacks lips]
Are we getting peer reviewed?
No. More of, uh, an informal observation.
Will they get in trouble?
- I don't think so.
- Okay.
So, uh, then nothing major went wrong
and there are no consequences?
Think you answered my question.
How's your project with Helm?
Is it something fun?
Deathly boring?
Definitely the latter.
Hmm.
Your sister went outside to get some air
and call your parents.
Oh.
Colorectal cancer and fertility studies?
Just educating myself.
I know you want things
to be better for Chloe.
She's my sister.
And you're also a surgeon.
We like to believe
we can solve everyone's problems.
I really thought there'd be other options,
but... [sighs] ...Wilson's right.
You know,
I've seen a lot of cancer patients
in my career.
And no matter the type or stage,
the treatment process... it's grueling.
Some people say the side effects of it
are just as horrible as the cancer itself.
Everyone has the same questions,
and they reckon with the same concerns.
Cancer is universal that way.
It's universal.
What if I can find a precedent
for protecting fertility
when treating other cancers?
Then I'd be willing to bet
it's relevant to colorectal cancer too.
Oh, Jo. Jo.
[gasps] Ben Warren. Oh, my God.
You missed me, I missed you.
It's great to be back.
I just gave someone a heparin drip
instead of prophylaxis.
How do I stop it?
Oh. Yeah, the new EMR system is confusing.
Okay. Type in the patient's MRN there.
- And then you are gonna click here, here.
- Okay.
- You're done.
- Okay. [sighs, chuckles]
I've had three careers. You'd think I'd
remember the first day is always rough.
It'll get better.
Kwan is lapping me,
and he's only been a doctor eight months.
You'll be fine.
You've been off fighting fires.
I went from splicing intestines
to delivering babies,
and I still have no idea what day it is,
and I'm a constant mess.
Yeah? What's new in your life?
Can you keep a secret?
- Yeah.
- [mutters]
Yasuda, are you okay?
I need your help.
Okay.
Hey. [sighs]
Turkey burgers from the cafeteria.
Listen... [smacks lips]
...I think earlier I might've...
Insinuated that you know the job
better than me?
- You're lucky I'm hungry.
- [chuckles]
[sighs] Hey,
would you ever get a butt lift?
Uh, no, no, no.
No, no. I'm not suggesting...
You are... You are perfect.
But there's a woman in the ER.
She just had one, and, uh, I don't get it.
- What don't you get?
- Well, it's a surgery with risks. And why?
So you can wear different clothes?
[chuckles]
Wait, you think that this woman
underwent anesthesia,
had surgeons cut into her glute,
suck fat from her belly
and put it back in her butt
just so that she could wear
different clothes?
I mean, why else would she do it?
Let me break it down for you.
The world that you live in
where you do a good job
and you get rewarded for it,
that is not the world that women live in.
In our world, you can be smarter,
you can work harder,
but the prettier person
who has a more desirable body
almost always gets ahead
because the people who decide that
are almost always men.
So before we rush to judge the woman
for being so desperate that she underwent
surgery to change her body,
maybe we should think about how
our culture prioritizes the wrong things
and think about how we can change that.
I was just asking.
- And I was just answering.
- [phone buzzing]
Sorry, I have to take this.
Um, thank you for the burger.
Yeah, no. I wanna review that.
[grunts] Never thought I'd say this,
but I am missing Pearl.
Is that your partner or your friend?
My booty pillow. [sighs]
These cheeks could use
a good cushion. [chuckles]
- Are you in more pain?
- A little. [sighs]
Well, the scans will be quick,
so just try to sit still.
[titters]
[Judith] I know what you're thinking.
Trust me, my family gave me grief
for getting surgery too.
But for 30 years,
no one blinked an eye at me.
I was the sidekick with the pancake butt.
[chuckles] But then, overnight,
I became the star.
I've never felt more empowered
in my own skin.
Forget the jobs that work from home
and the movies on the couch.
I'm planning on taking this beauty
all across town.
The labs are in.
White count is 18,000.
That can't be right. Are you sure
you're looking at the right value?
Yeah. I'm more than familiar
with our lab result system.
If you wanna rerun them,
I'll let Dr. Hunt know.
These numbers are off the charts.
Oh, scans are up.
You see that?
Extensive signs of infection
to the muscles along the fascial planes.
- [Judith] Are we done?
- [sigh]
Judith, I'm gonna have to
check your hip again.
- May I?
- Yeah.
- Is that...
- Necrotizing fasciitis.
- Someone help me with this gurney.
- What's going on? What's happening?
You have a fast-moving soft tissue
infection, but don't worry, we're faster.
[stammers] Page the attendings
and book an OR right now.
On my count. One, two, three.
[Levi breathes deeply]
I like that painting. [sighs]
You get to wake up to the sunrise
even when it's raining.
I thought you were gonna say
"even in the middle of the day."
- [moans] That too.
- Mm-hmm.
[grunts]
I, um...
I got it at an Italian restaurant.
Is it Nicoletti's?
No, it was a little café
in Cortona, Italy.
I was going through a rough time,
so I booked a red-eye to Florence.
And I told myself I would visit every
art museum between there and Vatican City.
I...
I strained my neck gazing at
Michelangelo's work in the Sistine Chapel.
- And, uh...
- [chuckles]
I don't know. When I saw that sunrise,
it lifted something up in me.
So, I asked the restaurant owner
if he would sell it to me.
You know how sometimes
you just feel a strong connection?
I do.
Page me as soon as his ABG gets back.
Dr. Ndugu's asking.
Dr. Griffith?
[clears throat]
So how was everything
with the patient in the ER?
Things seem smooth?
Everything appeared in control.
I don't think you have anything
to worry about on the case.
Mm-hmm.
Oh, you think or you know?
Are we talking about big booty Judy or...
Right.
[stammers, sighs]
Look, um, it's not that I don't think
he will succeed.
Um, I also wanna make sure
that he has an objective experience.
The same treatment as everyone.
And if I go down there,
my appearance in the room
takes away that objectivity.
I can spare another five minutes.
Thank you.
So you'd move my ovaries into my abdomen?
We'd move them up
and attach them to the abdominal wall
so they're out of the field of radiation.
Has this been done before?
Ovarian transposition
is often used to help preserve
the fertility of cervical cancer patients,
but there's no reason
it couldn't apply to your case.
I'll be able to have kids later?
There is a 50% to 80% success rate.
That's better than zero.
And if we can preserve
your ovarian function,
then you likely will not need
hormone replacements.
[gasps]
This is great.
Thank you so much.
Thank your sister.
She's the one who thought of it.
Can we do this today?
That way, I can start treatment sooner,
finish my last semester
before my scholarship runs out.
I should totally do this right now, right?
I mean, just get it done?
Okay. I'm gonna call Mom and Dad first,
but yes.
You want Dr. Webber
and Dr. Wilson to be the ones to do it.
And you can be in the operating room
with me.
I can't, Chloe.
Family's not allowed.
Oh, right.
Hey.
Think of it like
one of your cross country races.
It'll be over before you know it,
and I will be as close as I can be, okay?
[softly] Okay.
- Okay?
- Okay.
Let's do it.
[crunching]
Do you always eat
when you're scanning patients?
Well, I mean, technically,
he's not a patient.
And he's in a bag.
And dead.
[phone buzzes]
Uh, Yasuda's sister is getting surgery.
Is it an emergency?
[sighs] Doesn't seem like it.
They're waiting for an OR to open.
What's going on between you two?
- [sighs] Nothing.
- [phone buzzes]
Oh.
Is that her?
No, it's Maxine.
Spaghetti and meatballs for dinner.
Yasuda is not texting me.
She basically accused me
of having no empathy.
Well, her sister has cancer.
She's just stressed.
You know what's not going to
make her sister get better?
Being mean to me.
Really?
He can't hear me.
Heart rate's in the 140s,
systolic's around 100.
We broadened IV antibiotics
and started low-dose norepi.
Judith, we're taking you up to the OR
to remove the infected tissue
and stop it spreading, okay?
[sobbing] Are you gonna take my butt?
The infection seems to have spread
to your glute,
- but we won't know till we get to the OR.
- No, I want a second opinion.
There's no time for another opinion.
You have to trust us.
I don't understand.
I just fell on the sidewalk.
The bacteria must've got in
through the cut on your thigh.
It's rare, but it happens.
Do you know what it's like
to be invisible?
Well, if there were any other option,
we would tell you. I promise, Judith.
- [beeping continues]
- Judith? Judith? Judith?
Damn it. She's septic.
Come on. Come on. Come on.
Okay, let's go. Let's move.
- Where am I?
- Mr. Riley, hold on. I got you.
- I need a hand in here. Griffith!
- [nurse] He started crashing a minute ago.
I need to intubate.
- Push 30 of etomidate and 150 of sux.
- [nurse 2] On it.
- Where is Griffith?
- [nurse] I got the intubation tray.
All right. Let's get you some air.
Here we go. Here we go.
Okay. Come on.
Damn it.
Helm. Helm, get in here.
I need you to apply cricoid pressure.
- There?
- Higher.
Higher. Right there, right there.
There we go. I'm in.
All right.
Come on.
His sats aren't improving.
We need to get him on ECMO
before the hypoxemia puts too much
stress on his heart and he codes.
I need an ECMO machine right now!
[panting] What happened?
He was intubated,
but he wasn't oxygenating.
You'd know that
if you were monitoring like I asked.
I'm sorry. I ran down to
the emergency room to check...
I don't wanna hear it. Wait outside.
Helm, get the tube ready.
[Atticus] Okay.
I hit a pocket of fluid. Suction.
[all groan]
[Benson grunts] She's gonna be devastated
when she wakes up and it's all gone.
- At least she'll still be here.
- [Owen] If we can work fast enough.
We're gonna need another set of hands.
Warren, you ready to get in here?
Sure. Scalpel.
Good. Quick and intentional.
I can help if you need it.
Just keep up with the suction.
Actually, you know,
I could use a hand in here.
Uh, Kwan, you wanna help break up
some of this tissue?
Yeah.
Oh, I see healthy tissue.
[stammers] Yep, there it is.
Bleeding edges.
Nice work, boss.
Moving on to the superior aspect
of the thigh.
[Lucas sighs] Last one.
Do you remember your med school cadaver?
Yeah. Sixty-eight-year-old female,
lungs full of mets.
Uh, we assumed she was a smoker.
Named her Marge
and decided she was a trucker.
Mine was my grandma.
Uh, wait, you, uh, dissected
your grandmother?
What? God, no. No, no.
My... My dad's mom died before I was born,
and my mom really hated her.
So I... I kinda grew up without a grandma.
But we had been dissecting our cadaver
for weeks
before we finally took the towel
off her face.
And I remember looking at her
and thinking,
"She could be my grandma."
And I just hoped
that she didn't feel alone.
I hoped she felt that she was surrounded
by people who truly appreciated her.
I, uh...
I never thought about it
that way. [chuckles]
Yeah.
And then we cut open her neck
and her head and finished...
Um...
Could you transfer the scans
to the CDs by yourself?
[stutters] There's something
I really need to do.
Yeah?
Yeah, okay.
[♪ "Don't Let Go" playing]
♪ We've made it through winter ♪
[clears throat]
Hey, any, uh, news...
[chuckles] ...from the pit?
Just... Uh, how is he?
He's on ECMO and stable.
But I don't know
if he'll ever breathe on his own again.
I'm so sorry.
What were you doing in the ER
when my patients are up here?
Please explain that to me.
- Um, why don't we take a breath?
- I'm breathing just fine, thank you.
I was checking on a patient
for a colleague, and I...
- In the ER?
- Dr. Ndugu...
Dr. Bailey, hold on.
If-If I can't trust you
to follow simple instructions,
I can't have you on my service.
- Dr. Ndugu, I need a word in private.
- I asked you to step in because I...
♪ Follow you ♪
- ♪ I'll follow ♪
- ♪ Follow you ♪
- ♪ Follow you, follow you ♪
- ♪ I'll follow ♪
- ♪ Follow you ♪
We're about to start the anesthesia.
Are you ready?
[Jo] Okay.
Wait. Excuse me.
[Jules] Is it all right if I...
[Jules sighs]
Hi. I'm Jules. We met this morning.
I'm one of the interns.
I know who you are.
♪ I'll follow you ♪
♪ Follow you, follow you ♪
Okay. I asked Griffith to check on
a patient in the emergency room.
I didn't realize
that your patient was borderline critical.
She knew. She should've said no.
I'm her boss, right?
It's not her fault.
Why did you send her downstairs?
You're not working there today.
[stammers] I don't know. I...
[inhales sharply]
First day back in a while.
I wanted to see how things were going,
that's all.
Okay. Take it from the guy who married
and then divorced his boss.
Get out of your husband's way.
Uh, I beg your pardon?
I'm saying at home, you need to be a team.
At work, let him be his own person.
Hey. I'm sorry.
- I'm sorry, I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
- The appointment was at 5:00, right?
[sighs] I know. I just got so busy
with patients. I completely forgot.
You don't have to apologize.
DeLuca had to leave.
- We were gonna see the baby.
- Yeah, we'll just reschedule.
Wait. Come with me. [chuckles]
[♪ song playing]
[sighs]
Judith, how are you feeling?
You really have to ask?
[chuckles] You should
be feeling better soon.
We were able to remove
the infected tissue.
And we'll keep you in the ICU
for a few more days
to wash out the wound and make sure
there's no more necrotic tissue.
Okay, trauma. Kwan, come with me.
Check on the cultures,
and we'll see you downstairs.
Judith, I will come check on you soon,
okay?
♪ A little bit of good news ♪
[grunts]
I know it feels like you're going back
to an old version of yourself.
But I've learned when it feels
like you're losing ground,
you're still moving forward.
Everything you've learned,
everything you've experienced,
it all comes with you.
I can tell you what's not coming with me.
The $8,000 I spent on my butt.
No, but all that confidence you gained
after the lift,
we didn't take any of that.
Are you saying I have big butt energy?
- [laughs] I'm saying all is not lost.
- [Judith chuckles]
But if down the road
you decide you want reconstruction,
[clicks tongue] I know
a great plastic surgeon in Boston.
Now you're talking.
[laughs]
Get some rest.
♪ Someday I will look back ♪
♪ I hope I understand ♪
♪ Why I had to go through that ♪
She's doing well.
There were no complications.
And Dr. Webber says she should be able
to go home soon.
I'm sorry... [sighs] ...for what I said
earlier. Sometimes I can be such a...
Thank you for sitting with her.
You have no idea
how much that meant to her.
How much it meant to me.
Well, I knew you couldn't do it, so...
Didn't want her to be alone.
Oh. [sighs]
Thank you for everything.
Oh, I was glad to help.
You know, it's not easy to watch
someone you love fight cancer.
There'll be days you feel like
your heart's being ripped to pieces.
[sighs]
Remember to take care of yourself too.
[mouthing words] Thank you.
♪ Please, just give me a sign ♪
♪ I will learn ♪
♪ Please, just show me a sign ♪
Hey! You still haven't finished uploading
all the scans.
Yeah, I know.
Adams, they have this covered.
Hey, hey! Show some respect.
These people donated their bodies
so that future doctors
could learn how to help others
live longer, healthier lives.
Okay. Sorry.
I wanted to help.
Hey. Oh, aren't you supposed
to be getting the kids?
Yeah, well,
I thought we could grab a bite first.
Oh, I can, uh, either eat with you
or feed the kids,
but I don't have time for both.
- Do you not feel this?
- Feel what?
Ever since we got rehired, we haven't
had a single meal alone together.
We haven't had a conversation
that wasn't about surgery
or the kids' schedules
in almost three weeks.
Well, work has been busy.
But, you know,
we'll get back on track eventually.
It's just... [grunts]
It feels like we're not connecting,
you know?
It feels like there's something
eating away at this relationship.
And I... I know I stepped in it
more than once today...
No, it's... it's not just you.
[♪ "Talking About Hope" playing]
I feel it too. [sighs]
[Grey] When a patient codes in surgery,
the first thing we do
is remove their drape.
We need to see
if there's something we missed.
Is this a mistake?
Me being your boss.
[scoffs] When are you not my boss?
[imitating Miranda] "Ben,
can you take out the garbage?
Ooh, ooh, ooh, Ben, kill that spider.
Ben, why haven't you changed the light
in the refrigerator?"
Come on. Don't be cute.
You know what I mean.
We're professionals.
I'm not worried.
Okay.
But if it ever
gets uncomfortable for you...
I will let you know.
I promise.
♪ But I know my name ♪
Let's get home
so I can get some sleep. [grunts]
I have pre-rounds before sunrise.
- Welcome back, Dr. Warren.
- Oh.
[Grey] Much like in surgery,
sometimes in life we lose sight
of the bigger picture.
♪ I'm not talking 'bout fire ♪
Mimi? [sighs]
Hey.
How are you feeling?
Tired.
And I kinda want a doughnut.
[chuckles]
Go back to sleep. You need rest.
- But, Mimi...
- We will get doughnuts.
[chuckles]
[softly] Thanks for everything.
I didn't do anything.
I couldn't even be in your surgery,
remember?
I meant as my sister.
[shushes, whispers] Close your eyes.
Good.
[sighs]
♪ I fell in love with you ♪
[Jules] Hi.
- [softly] Hey.
- [Jules] We brought things.
- How's she doing?
- Good.
She's already asking
about snacks. [chuckles]
- That tracks.
- [Mika] Yeah.
We'll let you both sleep.
Thanks, uh, for all the stuff.
We also took all of your shifts
for the next week
so you can spend time with Chloe.
Thank you, guys.
[Grey] When we're stressed or worried,
it can be hard to see
the things that are going well.
♪ And I'm not talking 'bout hope ♪
♪ I'm not talking 'bout fire ♪
♪ I'm just tryna make sense
Of this desire ♪
♪ So put your hand on my head ♪
♪ And put your hand on my heart ♪
[Grey] And when we're floating
on cloud nine,
it's just as easy to miss red flags.
Expanding our perspective
can give us a better, more accurate view
of ourselves and the world.
I don't see anything. Do you?
No, just my intestines.
- Stop moving it around.
- [both chuckle]
Well, I still don't see anything.
- [Jo gasps]
- Wait. Is that...
Yeah, there's our baby.
And there's the heartbeat!
You don't see it, do you? See right there?
And also there.
Oh, my God!
- Twins!
- Twins?
[sighs]
[Grey] It may end up being more
than you could have ever imagined.